<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>works on Redgum &amp; Rust</title><link>http://redgumandrust.com.au/tags/works/</link><description>Recent content in works on Redgum &amp; Rust</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="http://redgumandrust.com.au/tags/works/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Iron Mirror 1</title><link>http://redgumandrust.com.au/works/fragments/iron-mirror-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://redgumandrust.com.au/works/fragments/iron-mirror-1/</guid><description>Iron Mirror 1 is a model for a piece that I never completed. It had a slightly complicated gestation.
I Nearly Make a Table&amp;hellip; I initially made a circular frame for sitting a piece of tempered glass into. I made the frame from strip steel on a machine called a Ring Roller, that passes the work over two undriven rollers in a row with a third driven roller pressing down on the work, so by repeated passes it forms a perfect circle (apart from the ends, which remain straight as they can&amp;rsquo;t go through the machine).</description></item><item><title>Sign for Footscray Maker Lab</title><link>http://redgumandrust.com.au/works/fragments/fml-sign/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://redgumandrust.com.au/works/fragments/fml-sign/</guid><description>FML Sign was a sign for the shared studio space &amp;ldquo;Footscray Maker Lab&amp;rdquo; or FML in inner Melbourne. Situated in a semi-derelict warehouse that the owners' only leased to us as I suspect no-one else would rent it. It was a noted rave venue in the 90s, and there was plenty of graffiti in the place, but even the ravers thought it too shabby and moved on. It was an interesting experience at a difficult personal time, and certainly gave me something else to think about.</description></item><item><title>Sound Wave</title><link>http://redgumandrust.com.au/works/fragments/sound-wave/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://redgumandrust.com.au/works/fragments/sound-wave/</guid><description>Sound Wave was easily my biggest and heaviest sculpture, 2.4m high and 250Kg! Like most of my ideas the actual result differed from the concept.
My concept was inspired by a fern shoot bursting through the ground. It always amazes me how something as soft as a fern shoot can break through hard earth and push through layers of packed bark and forest trash considering that it is about the strength of an asparagas stalk.</description></item><item><title>Sunbeam</title><link>http://redgumandrust.com.au/works/misc/sunbeam/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://redgumandrust.com.au/works/misc/sunbeam/</guid><description>Sunbeam was a long time in the making. The inspiritational piece for mewas when I picked up an old Sunbeam brand cake mixer on hard rubbish, and then I dropped it and broke off the handle, which was made of brittle bakelite. I then removed the handle, and the hole in the top looked like a cockpit, with the lovely 50s design of the mixer forming the body of a retro-futuristic vehicle.</description></item><item><title>Good Ship Hobo</title><link>http://redgumandrust.com.au/works/misc/good-ship-hobo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://redgumandrust.com.au/works/misc/good-ship-hobo/</guid><description>The Good Ship Hobo was a collaboration with Claude Ciccione of Belgrave. I made the hull out of an upright from a set of Brownbuilt steel shelves, the row of holes where the shelves could be fixed looked to me like portholes. I did get the hull welded up by a professional welder who is also an artist. Claude and I worked on the trimmings on the deck together, using mainly my bits &amp;amp; pieces.</description></item><item><title>I Made It Myself</title><link>http://redgumandrust.com.au/works/fragments/i-made-it-myself/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://redgumandrust.com.au/works/fragments/i-made-it-myself/</guid><description>I made I Made It Myself for a recycled art show held in Kingston in 2022. The theme was &amp;ldquo;Messages of Hope&amp;rdquo; and the direction was to make a mailbox. I was rather pleased that I got first prize, here&amp;rsquo;s me &amp;amp; the Mayor Paula Wreidt at the opening.
Materials The box is made of scrap clear acrylic glued together. I have yet to find a good glue for acrylic, even bathroom silicone (the sort that smells like ants) doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to hold very well.</description></item><item><title>Miss New Zealand</title><link>http://redgumandrust.com.au/works/figures/miss-new-zealand/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://redgumandrust.com.au/works/figures/miss-new-zealand/</guid><description>Miss New Zealand&amp;rsquo;s name was inspired by the mascot for the Sydney Mardi Gras one year, who was a 1950&amp;rsquo;s young lady in twinset &amp;amp; pearls, who obviously never went out without her coat, hat and gloves.
The starting point was the novelty Harrods branded padlock, it was an obvious handbag. Her body is a trailer plug, arms from a gas lighter and hands are electrical terminals. Her shoes are also some sort of electrical clippy thing.</description></item><item><title>The Reader</title><link>http://redgumandrust.com.au/works/figures/the-reader/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://redgumandrust.com.au/works/figures/the-reader/</guid><description>The Reader is just made to sit on a shelf and keeps very much to herself (I always think of it as a &amp;ldquo;her&amp;rdquo;). I&amp;rsquo;m not sure what she&amp;rsquo;s made of, just some rusty iron I picked up, I do remember being inspired by the wonderful textures that rust gives to iron after a few years or decades.
Her legs are a pair of hinges from an old Singer sewing machine that allowed it to fold away into the wooden base.</description></item></channel></rss>