<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>favourites on Redgum &amp; Rust</title><link>http://redgumandrust.com.au/tags/favourites/</link><description>Recent content in favourites on Redgum &amp; Rust</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="http://redgumandrust.com.au/tags/favourites/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Celeste Goes Dancing</title><link>http://redgumandrust.com.au/works/figures/celeste-goes-dancing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://redgumandrust.com.au/works/figures/celeste-goes-dancing/</guid><description>Celeste Goes Dancing Size: base 17cm x 17cm; height 40cm. Materials: electric heater base, reproduction blender, lampshade, chandelier parts, door lock, salvaged wood, Christmas lights. Date: 2015. Note: requires mains 240V power.
Celeste Goes Dancing was my earliest attempt at a kinetic (moving) sculpture. The name comes from a book of South American fantastic short stories that I owned when I was into the magical realism style, I remember nothing about the book apart that it was my introduction to the wonder of Jorge Luis Borges, so it deserves to be memorialised.</description></item><item><title>Sound Wave</title><link>http://redgumandrust.com.au/works/fragments/sound-wave/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://redgumandrust.com.au/works/fragments/sound-wave/</guid><description>Sound Wave was easily my biggest and heaviest sculpture, 2.4m high and over 250Kg as that&amp;rsquo;s where my scale stops! Like most of my ideas the actual result differed from the concept.
My concept was inspired by a fern shoot bursting through the ground. It always amazes me how something as soft as a fern shoot can break through hard earth and push through layers of packed bark and forest trash considering that it is about the strength of an asparagas stalk.</description></item><item><title>Sunbeam</title><link>http://redgumandrust.com.au/works/misc/sunbeam/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://redgumandrust.com.au/works/misc/sunbeam/</guid><description>Sunbeam was a long time in the making. The inspiritational piece for mewas when I picked up an old Sunbeam brand cake mixer on hard rubbish, and then I dropped it and broke off the handle, which was made of brittle bakelite. I then removed the handle, and the hole in the top looked like a cockpit, with the lovely 50s design of the mixer forming the body of a retro-futuristic vehicle.</description></item></channel></rss>