<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>misc on Redgum &amp; Rust</title><link>http://redgumandrust.com.au/tags/misc/</link><description>Recent content in misc on Redgum &amp; Rust</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="http://redgumandrust.com.au/tags/misc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Coffee Table</title><link>http://redgumandrust.com.au/works/misc/coffee-table/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://redgumandrust.com.au/works/misc/coffee-table/</guid><description>One of my massive furniture pieces. I needed a coffee table for my flat, and just be a happy coincidence there was a large truck motor hanging around at my shared studio space &amp;ldquo;Footscray Maker Lab&amp;rdquo; or FML; as so often happens in such places some tenant had acquired an item and then left, usually owing rent, so their abandoned items just hung around taking up space. It was mounted on a heavy trolley so that it could be moved with difficulty as it weighed half a ton at least.</description></item><item><title>Domestic Goddess</title><link>http://redgumandrust.com.au/works/misc/domestic-goddess/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://redgumandrust.com.au/works/misc/domestic-goddess/</guid><description>Domestic Goddess Height: 37cm
Materials: Coffee pot, lamp parts, glass beads, curtain rings, table forks.
Date: 2016
Domestic Goddess is a piece of folk art, so like all such she&amp;rsquo;s not particularly original, you will find plenty like her out there in internet land. Folk art endlessly reuses motifs: Domestic Goddess' hands are table forks and she lives in a piece of retro kitchenalia. My kids really used to like that her earrings are curtain rings; a favourite movie was Planes, Trains and Automobiles where John Candy&amp;rsquo;s character makes quick money peddling shower curtain rings to various people, telling two young teens girls that as earrings &amp;ldquo;You know something?</description></item><item><title>Fish Away: Nature Transforms</title><link>http://redgumandrust.com.au/works/misc/fish-away/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://redgumandrust.com.au/works/misc/fish-away/</guid><description>Size: width 60cm, height 40cm, depth 9cm. Materials: Antique cast iron fragment, purpose unknown, 1950’s aluminium lamp shade, Victorian shoe tree, plumber’s snake, vintage indicator lamp, fused plastic bags, scrap timber, acrylic sheet from White Night artwork; all recycled. RGB LED strip &amp;amp; programmable controller from Aliexpress. Date: 2018, 2019. Note: requires a USB socket for power, such as a USB charger
I regret the wanky title, the piece was made for the Dandenong Ranges Artists Open Studios Exhibition 2019, and they chose the theme &amp;ldquo;Alchemy&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Still Ahead</title><link>http://redgumandrust.com.au/works/misc/still-ahead/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://redgumandrust.com.au/works/misc/still-ahead/</guid><description>Details Size: 30cm wide x 40cm high wall hanging; 30cmm deep.
Materials: Brass coffeepot, saucepan lid, lighting fixture parts, tongs, curtain rod ends, old marbles, industrial electrical plug parts, Christmas lights, old phone cable, tea tray.
Date: 2023. Note: requires USB for lights.
Art From Trash Still Ahead was made for the annual &amp;ldquo;Art From Trash&amp;rdquo; art show in 2023 at the Long Gallery, Salamanca Arts Centre, Hobart. Organised by South Hobart Tip Shop, perhaps the premier tip shop in the state, though Mornington is pretty good as well.</description></item><item><title>Sunbeam</title><link>http://redgumandrust.com.au/works/misc/sunbeam/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://redgumandrust.com.au/works/misc/sunbeam/</guid><description>Sunbeam was a long time in the making. The inspiritational moment for me was when I picked up an old Sunbeam brand cake mixer on hard rubbish, and then I dropped it and broke off the handle, which was made of brittle bakelite. I then removed the handle, and the hole in the top looked like a cockpit, with the lovely 50s design of the mixer forming the body of a retro-futuristic vehicle.</description></item><item><title>Good Ship Hobo</title><link>http://redgumandrust.com.au/works/misc/good-ship-hobo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://redgumandrust.com.au/works/misc/good-ship-hobo/</guid><description>The Good Ship Hobo was a collaboration with Claude Ciccione of Belgrave. I made the hull out of an upright from a set of Brownbuilt steel shelves, the row of holes where the shelves could be fixed looked to me like portholes. I did get the hull welded up by a professional welder who is also an artist. Claude and I worked on the trimmings on the deck together, using mainly my bits &amp;amp; pieces.</description></item><item><title>My Happy Place</title><link>http://redgumandrust.com.au/works/misc/my-happy-place/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://redgumandrust.com.au/works/misc/my-happy-place/</guid><description>Details Size: 50cm x 50cm x 60cm high.
Materials: Lampshade and microwave oven plate from tip shop, legs are recycled furniture timber. Lights recycled Xmas decorations. Charger from e-waste. Books from my library, from op-shops. Reader made from miscellaneous workshop junk.
Date: 2023.
Note: requires mains power for lights.
Salvaged Art Exhibition Kingston 2023 I made My Happy Place for a recycled art show held in Kingston in 2023 (I entered I Made It Myself in 2021, the show is biennial).</description></item></channel></rss>