<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>misc on Redgum &amp; Rust</title><link>http://redgumandrust.com.au/tags/misc/</link><description>Recent content in misc on Redgum &amp; Rust</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="http://redgumandrust.com.au/tags/misc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Fml Sign</title><link>http://redgumandrust.com.au/works/misc/fml-sign/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://redgumandrust.com.au/works/misc/fml-sign/</guid><description>FML Sign was a sign for the shared studio space &amp;ldquo;Footscray Maker Lab&amp;rdquo; or FML in inner Melbourne. Situated in a semi-derelict warehouse that the owners' only leased to us as I suspect no-one else would rent it. It wasanoted rave venue in the 90s, and there was plenty of graffiti in the place. It was an interesting experience at a difficult personal time, and certainly gave me something else to think about.</description></item><item><title>Sunbeam</title><link>http://redgumandrust.com.au/works/misc/sunbeam/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://redgumandrust.com.au/works/misc/sunbeam/</guid><description>Sunbeam was a long time in the making. The inspiritational piece for mewas when I picked up an old Sunbeam brand cake mixer on hard rubbish, and then I dropped it and broke off the handle, which was made of brittle bakelite. I then removed the handle, and the hole in the top looked like a cockpit, with the lovely 50s design of the mixer forming the body of a retro-futuristic vehicle.</description></item><item><title>Good Ship Hobo</title><link>http://redgumandrust.com.au/works/misc/good-ship-hobo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://redgumandrust.com.au/works/misc/good-ship-hobo/</guid><description>The Good Ship Hobo was a collaboration with Claude Ciccione of Belgrave. I made the hull out of abroken upright from a set of Brownbuilt steel shelves, the row of holes where the shelves could be fixed looked to me like portholes. I did get the hull welded up by a professional welder who is also an artist. Claude and I worked on the trimmings on the deck together, using mainly my bits &amp;amp; pieces.</description></item><item><title>I Made It Myself</title><link>http://redgumandrust.com.au/works/misc/i-made-it-myself/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://redgumandrust.com.au/works/misc/i-made-it-myself/</guid><description>I made I Made It Myself for a recycled art show held in Kingston in 2022. The theme was &amp;ldquo;Messages of Hope&amp;rdquo; and the direction was to make a mailbox. I was rather pleased that I got first prize, heres me &amp;amp; the Mayor Paula Wreidt at the opening.
Materials The box is made of scrap clear acrylic glued together. I have yet to find a good glue for acrylic, even bathroom silicone (the sort that smells like ants) doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to hold very well.</description></item></channel></rss>